apexlearning.com 2018-09-07

# Privacy Policy | Apex Learning

### The Purpose of this Privacy Policy

In this Privacy Policy Apex Learning Inc. is referred to as " **Apex Learning** ," " **we** ," " **us** ," or " **our"** and you, the end user, are referred to as " **you** " or " **your** ".

Certain Apex Learning® websites are freely accessible (" **Apex Learning Corporate Websites** "). Other Apex Learning websites are restricted to those who are authorized to access them by Apex Learning and have a user name and password ( **"Apex Learning Customer Websites** "); these Apex Learning Customer Websites include any Apex Learning online service offering made available through such websites (" **Apex Online Services** ").

This Privacy Policy describes the type of information we may collect from users through both the Apex Learning Corporate and Customer Websites (the **"Apex Learning Websites** "), how we use that information, and with whom we may share it.

The Apex Learning Websites include links to websites operated by others. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such third parties, and this policy does not apply to any information collected by such third party websites.

The links below will take you directly to the specific section of this Privacy Policy. 

How We May Collect Personal Information

Types of Personal Information Collected

How Information is Used and Shared

Business Transfers

Third Parties

Children and Our Privacy Policy

Non-Personal User Information

Cookies

Steps You Can Take to Protect Your Privacy

Modification of this Privacy Policy

Contact Information

### How We May Collect Personal Information

We may collect information often referred to as “personally identifiable information,” “personal information,” or “personal data” (collectively **“Personal Information”** ) when you obtain a user name and password, when you participate in an Apex Online Service or when you otherwise communicate with us through an Apex Learning Website or otherwise. We may also obtain your Personal Information through an Apex Learning Website if it is submitted by a representative of the institution (such as a school, school district, state department of education or other educational organization) or by the individual (such as a parent or guardian) funding your participation in the Apex Online Service (" **Sponsoring Organization** ").

### Types of Personal Information Collected

We may collect the following types of Personal Information at the Apex Learning Websites:

1\. When a student, or a teacher, school administrator or representative of a Sponsoring Organization on behalf of a student, obtains a user name and password or enrolls in the Apex Online Service, we may request the following Personal Information:

  * student name and email address
  * school name
  * school or homeschool address
  * student phone number
  * parent or guardian contact information for the student
  * credit card information for the student

2\. When a student participates in Apex Course activities, information about the student activity (e.g. time spent on certain problems, number of quiz attempts), student activity scores and grades are collected in a password-protected location with limited access by the student, the student's parent(s)/guardian(s), the student's teacher, administrators from the student's school and/or personnel from the student's Sponsoring Organization.

3\. When a teacher, school administrator or personnel from a Sponsoring Organization obtains a user name and password, we may request the following Personal Information:

  * name and email address
  * school or organization name
  * school or organization address
  * school or organization phone number
  * credit card information for the school or organization

4\.  You may participate in message boards, forums or chats in connection with your use of Apex Online Services, where the information you share (including any personal information) can be viewed and used by other users of the Apex Online Services participating in the message boards, forums or chats.

### How Information Is Used and Shared

**Apex Online Services and Support**. We may use your Personal Information to provide the Apex Online Service, including user support, to you and your school or Sponsoring Organization as well as to improve Apex Online Services. **Apex Learning Communications.** For users other than students, we may send you communications about our offerings from time to time. If you do not want to receive these communications you can opt out by sending an email to [support@apexlearning.com](mailto:support@apexlearning.com) or by such other manner as may be indicated in such communications. **Grades, Progress & Usage.** We may share with your coach (e.g., parent or guardian), teacher, school and Sponsoring Organization information about student grades, progress or usage, including but not limited to, student activity scores, student course grades, student progress and utilization by students or teachers of the Apex Learning Websites. **Contact Information.** Your contact information may be shared with your teacher, school and Sponsoring Organization. If you enroll in one of the Apex Online Service offerings where the instruction for that offering is provided by an online Apex Learning teacher, your name, email address, school, phone number and state of residence will be shared with your online teacher. Your name and email address will be shared with other students participating in the same section of your Apex Online Service. Also, if you are a student or teacher, we may use your name, contact information, and school information to associate you with your Sponsoring Organization so you can gain access to the relevant Apex Online Service. **Legal Requirements.** Apex Learning may disclose your Personal Information if we have a good faith belief that it is necessary in order to: (1) comply with any applicable federal, state or local law or regulation, including to comply with any subpoena, warrant, court order, or other legal process to which Apex Learning is subject; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Apex Learning; (3) protect the personal safety of you, other users of Apex Online Services or the public; or (4) to ensure compliance with our Terms of Use for the Apex Learning Websites. Apex Learning cooperates with law enforcement and other third parties to enforce laws, intellectual property, and other rights. We may report suspicious activity to law enforcement for prosecution.  **Vendors.   **From time to time we may share your Personal Information with third party vendors that we engage to assist us in maintaining, supporting, or providing Apex Online Services.  In such event, we contractually require the vendor to use such Personal Information only as reasonably necessary to perform services for us and to maintain the confidentiality of such Personal Information.

### Business Transfers

Information about Apex Learning Websites users, including Personal Information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, sale of company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which Personal Information could be transferred to third parties as one of the business assets of Apex Learning.

### Third Parties

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose your Personal Information to third parties. Apex Learning may, however, use for its own purposes, aggregate information that does not identify you personally, or share aggregate information about our users with business partners, sponsors, and other third parties. For example, we may tell a business partner that x percent of Apex Learning's students are from the West Coast and y percent from the Southern U.S.

### Children and Our Privacy Policy

Children under 13 years of age ( **“Child”** or **“Children”** ) may be registered to use certain Apex Online Services by a Sponsoring Organization.  In such event, we may collect and use Personal Information from such a Child as described in this Privacy Policy, to provide the Apex Online Service to the Sponsoring Organization and for no other commercial purpose.  A parent may review or terminate their Child’s registration, and refuse to permit the further collection or use of their Child’s Personal Information, at any time by contacting us or the Child’s Sponsoring Organization.  If a parent terminates a Child’s registration, we will delete any and all Personal Information provided to us in connection with the registration.  In any event, we will delete a Child’s Personal Information once the information is no longer needed for its educational purpose. 

### Non-Personal User Information

Apex Learning seeks to provide a high-quality learning experience and may use various technologies to record certain technical information from your browser or device, including standard log files, clear GIFs, or pixel tags. This technical information may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, device or browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring or exit pages, clickstream data, operating system, and session dates and times. The data will help in understanding the user experience and allow website improvements and a customized functionality.

### Cookies

Cookies are small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters enabling us to remember information about your activities during your website visit. Session cookies are eliminated after a browser is closed while persistent cookies remain and may be used by your browser on subsequent website visits. Apex Learning may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to help us provide you with a personalized learning experience. You can remove a persistent cookie at any time, however, this may eliminate certain services and features. We do not store in cookies any passwords, credit card information or information that personally identifies you.

### Steps You Can Take to Protect Your Privacy

Links to Other Websites. You should be aware that when you are on any Apex Learning Website, you could be directed by links or otherwise to other websites hosted by third parties. We do not endorse those websites. For example, if you "click" a link to a third party site we have listed on one of the pages on the Apex Learning Websites, the "click" takes you off the applicable Apex Learning Websites. Apex Learning is not responsible for the content or information collection practices of any third party websites. Please note that these websites may have privacy policies that differ from this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review and understand their privacy practices before providing them with information.

What You Disclose. Please keep in mind that whenever you give out Personal Information online - for example, via message boards, forums, or chats - that information can be viewed and used by people that you do not know, including but not limited to other students who access the Apex Learning Websites. Apex Learning does not control their use of that information.

Security.  Apex Learning uses various security procedures and practices (including administrative, technical, and physical safeguards) to protect your Personal Information.  No security measure, however, is guaranteed.  Apex Learning does not ensure or warrant the security of any personal or other information you provide to us.  You can help protect your Personal Information by using strong passwords for the Apex Online Services and guarding access to those passwords.

### Modification of this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we do so, we will post the modified Privacy Policy on the Apex Learning Websites with an updated “Revision Date”.  If we make a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will provide a prominent notice (e.g., on our home page).  Any revisions will be effective upon posting except that we will give you or your Sponsoring Organization choices before using any of your Personal Information collected under a prior version of the Privacy Policy in a manner that is inconsistent with the Privacy Policy terms under which the information was initially provided.

### Contact Information

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact our support department at: Apex Learning Inc. 1215 Fourth Ave., Suite 1500 Seattle, WA 98161 or via email at: [support@apexlearning.com](mailto:support@apexlearning.com). In the U.S. you may also call us toll-free at: 1 (800) 453-1454. 

Copyright © 2017 Apex Learning Inc. Apex Learning® and the Apex Learning logo are either registered trademarks or trademarks of Apex Learning Inc.

Revision Date: September 19, 2017
